<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[ourbucketl.ist]]></title><description><![CDATA[Travel Blog]]></description><link>https://danjayrose.github.io/ourbucketl.ist/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 01:04:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Rio De Janeiro]]></title><description><![CDATA[Arriving Before we left for Rio, we were told in many ways about how dangerous it is. We did a bit of research the night before and read…]]></description><link>https://danjayrose.github.io/ourbucketl.ist//rio-de-janeiro/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://danjayrose.github.io/ourbucketl.ist//rio-de-janeiro/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Arriving&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we left for Rio, we were told in many ways about how dangerous it is. We did a bit of research the night before and read about the trouble following Rio Olympics 2016; the government promised to make the favela’s better, arrested some people, the Olympics came and went and the government didn’t follow through with any of their promises and improve thing, resulting in violence to escalate. We looked on google maps and seemed to be surrounded by favela’s and then read about a bank robbery in Botofogo in the touristic area and that the military had taken over the city. The guy running the hostel we were staying at had also warned us not to take money out at the airport due to credit cards being cloned. To make matters worse, when we arrived in Portugal for a one night stop over on the way, the lady running the hostel told us about her daughter who had been to Carnival a few weeks ago. She had been staying in Leblon, an area close to the biggest favela in Rio, Rochina, and had heard gunshots in Leblon and saw 100 people running away from the problems. She warned us to be careful. Me and Dan questioned why we were going to Rio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a horrendous flight with Air Maroc we were picked up by the hostel as it was late, the driver pulled up in a Fiat with absolutely blacked out windows and drove us through the streets of Rio, we managed to see Christ the Redeemer all lit up on the hill. No crimes were witnessed in our first hour of Rio. However  at traffic lights we heard people chanting and I started to think there was going to be a protest or some sort of gang violence around the corner, turned out it was football fans chanting in the local pub following a Flamengo goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Beaches&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went firstly to Gloria Beach, which the guy at the hostel had said was walkable. It was around a 25 minute walk and we took no electronics with us due to worrying about being mugged. However, our visit was trouble free, we didn’t even get harrassed on the beach. The sand was white and we had a great view of Sugarloaf Mountain and Christ when he didn’t disappear behind the clouds. The people selling beer and drinks were super friendly and it seemed to be full of locals running and sunbathing. We then got an Uber to Copacabana beach as it is so infamous, big mistake. Every thirty seconds someone was in our face trying to sell something, sunglasses, empanadas, bikinis, canga, caipirinhas and weed. We got an Uber back to the hostel as it was an hour and a half walk and we still weren’t brave enough to use the Subway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our last day in Rio, we did a walking tour of the Copacabana and Ipanema area. Our guide told us about the World Cup and how everyone gathers on the beach to watch the games.
and cried on the beach and showed us the place where “The Girl from Ipanema” was written. We went to Lagoa Rodrigues de Freitas and was given Biscoto Globo, a weird banana sweet and drank some Guarana, an energy drink that pre-exists red bull and tastes just the same. We watched the sun, sort of, set over the lake and Christ peeped out of the clouds for about 30 seconds just to rub our noses in the fact that we hadn’t been able to see him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day was Alan’s Birthday. He timed that perfectly into our trip. We did a free walking tour in the morning of Downtown and Lapa. We tried Coxinhas, breaded chicken balls with cheese inside and ended up at the bright tiled steps ‘Escadaria Selaron’ created by Jorge Selaron. They were really bright and vibrant and one of my favourite bits of the city. We were a little braver this day and I did take my camera out with me as I was on a walking tour. On the tour, a dutch girl had told us that she had managed to see Christ yesterday and had got an Uber up and down which was only €5 each way. She said it was cloudy and showed us the photo’s, you could just about make out his arms but couldn’t see his face or the city from such a height. We decided to take our chances and after a quick beer and a Subway took an Uber up to the top. Our driver spoke zero English and at one point tried to turn into the favela on the hill going up to Christ the Redeemer, luckily there was a visitor guide who either turned him away or gave him directions. After getting to the top, we went to buy our ticket, only to be told that there was no visibility at all and the live camera on Christ was just pure white from the cloud. We waited for some time and the boys had more beers but in the end had to give up. We went to a local restaurant in the evening called Os Ximenes, where we had two massive steaks, Brazilian sausage, scrambled egg in Farofa, a tasteless brazilian flour, rice and chips. It was delicious although covered in garlic. Alan gave it 3.5 burgers. As it was Alz’s 31st Birthday we went for some drinks to celebrate in a bar with a live jazz band. Alz ordered a beer and the waiter brought over three teeny tiny glasses and split the beer between three of us. It turned out to be something people do everywhere, share 600ml bottles of beer, not get one each, something difficult for a Brit to get used to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day three brought the scariest thunderstorm, the thunder and lightening came at the same time and was so loud that the lady by the tram line as we were waiting to cross the road, grabbed Alz’s arm. We were a little more confident this day and walked to Olympic Boulevard to see the mural by Eduardo Kobra, possibly the best street art we’ve seen. We kept checking the Christ to see if we could see him but he remained hidden behind the clouds pretty much all day. So, instead we went to the Mayan inspired Cathedral, which was ugly, but as Dan repeated ‘beauty comes from within’. We went for a walk to Santa Teresa, where Alz managed to split his trousers jumping up a step. After a very long uphill climb from Lapa to Santa Teresa we saw the view over Rio from Parque Das Ruinas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last day, last chance to see Christ and no such luck. The cloud was so thick we couldn’t even see the mountain he was on. So instead we went to the Museum of Modern Art and the National Historic Museum.
Verdict on Rio; as long as you’re&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Leaving the UK]]></title><description><![CDATA[Our first night is a stop over in Lisbon and although very early to be writing a travel blog, given that we haven’t even reached the first…]]></description><link>https://danjayrose.github.io/ourbucketl.ist//leaving-the-UK/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://danjayrose.github.io/ourbucketl.ist//leaving-the-UK/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Our first night is a stop over in Lisbon and although very early to be writing a travel blog, given that we haven’t even reached the first destination, Dan is still building it and wanted me to test it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a long drive to Luton (thanks Grandave) and having everything crossed that &lt;em&gt;‘The Beast from the East’&lt;/em&gt; would stay away until our flight had taken off, we arrived in a very rainy Lisbon at around 20:00. We’re staying in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4ulisbon.com/pt-pt&quot;&gt;4U Lisbon Guesthouse&lt;/a&gt; which is about 5 minutes from the airport and has 80p beers in the help yourself fridge. The lady who showed us to our room was very chatty and spent 10 minutes telling us about her daughters very recent trip to Rio de Janiero where men tried to steal her phone and she continued to tell us that her daughter heard gunfire and saw hundreds of people running away from the noise. Not worrying at all. We also found out that her son is a pilot and spent the last three months in Africa. Note to self: must get used to the small talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;//ourbucketl.ist/static/plane-f2f3bb1649cd9c53633ac84b11c673aa-b75f4.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
  
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; ; max-width: 700px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 75%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAPABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwAAAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAMFAv/EABYBAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIAAf/aAAwDAQACEAMQAAABayRhGsRjL//EABsQAAMAAgMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAhESBBMU/9oACAEBAAEFAly0emMd8E0mbLOx/8QAFREBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAARD/2gAIAQMBAT8BJ//EABQRAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABD/2gAIAQIBAT8BP//EABsQAAEEAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAADECEyETGB/9oACAEBAAY/ApTx0qVaNN//xAAaEAEAAgMBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABABEhMVFB/9oACAEBAAE/IcWiC+m+XFtKKI+diylef//aAAwDAQACAAMAAAAQcP8A/8QAFhEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEh/9oACAEDAQE/EKY//8QAFhEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAER/9oACAECAQE/EK2v/8QAHhAAAgICAgMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREAITFBUWFxgZH/2gAIAQEAAT8QwT5LX4xLQTiA1q1CTT8iADBA2hxzUPg9KUuO/c//2Q==&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
        alt=&quot;alt text&quot;
        title=&quot;Logo Title Text 1&quot;
        src=&quot;//ourbucketl.ist/static/plane-f2f3bb1649cd9c53633ac84b11c673aa-f3a32.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;//ourbucketl.ist/static/plane-f2f3bb1649cd9c53633ac84b11c673aa-6ba01.jpg 175w,
//ourbucketl.ist/static/plane-f2f3bb1649cd9c53633ac84b11c673aa-b8ff8.jpg 350w,
//ourbucketl.ist/static/plane-f2f3bb1649cd9c53633ac84b11c673aa-f3a32.jpg 700w,
//ourbucketl.ist/static/plane-f2f3bb1649cd9c53633ac84b11c673aa-61d28.jpg 1050w,
//ourbucketl.ist/static/plane-f2f3bb1649cd9c53633ac84b11c673aa-be74e.jpg 1400w,
//ourbucketl.ist/static/plane-f2f3bb1649cd9c53633ac84b11c673aa-bf62f.jpg 2100w,
//ourbucketl.ist/static/plane-f2f3bb1649cd9c53633ac84b11c673aa-b75f4.jpg 4032w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;
      /&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan didn’t fancy the snail resturant round the corner, so we had a Boots meal deal for dinner and the only time we left the guesthouse was to find an ATM to pay for the transfer in the morning, given that there is going to be continual rain and thunderstorms. Glad we went for the walk though as we bumped into a French Bulldog, who thoroughly enjoyed being stroked and who’s owner covered me with an umbrella for 5 minutes whilst he told me how his Frenchie had grown out of all of his coats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s still feeling very surreal that we won’t be coming back until November, my brain really can’t comprehend how long that is and even Dan shed a tear when he said goodbye to his Dad at the airport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going to enjoy our penultimate Alan-free evening.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>